RG 004:001, Andover Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Andover Probate Court records
1787-1946
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Andover District)
31.75 cubic feet
Probate record books, 1849-1941; Probate files, 1787-1946.
RG004_001
1912-001 and 2013-015
Historical Note
Andover, Tolland County, Town established in 1748, Parent Towns: Coventry and Hebron
The Andover Probate District was constituted June 27, 1851, from the Hebron Probate District. It served the municipalities of Andover, Bolton, and Columbia. At one time it also served the town of Eastford, May 1847 - June 20, 1849. The Andover Probate District merged on January 5, 2011 with the Manchester Probate District to create the Greater Manchester Probate District which serves the municipalities of Andover, Bolton, Columbia, and Manchester.
Town of Andover, Probate District chronology:
May 1848-June 26, 1851, Hebron District
June 27, 1851- January 4, 2011, Andover District
January 5, 2011-Present, Greater Manchester District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1849-1941. Contact the probate court to access original record books numbered greaster than 38. When the Andover district was created in 1851 from the Hebron district, the Hebron district record books numbered 1 through 21 remained in Andover where the court had been held. The newly created Andover district started the numbering of that court's record books with number 22. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1787-1946. Probate files dating 1787-1850 are from the Hebron District of which Andover was a part of during that time. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1787-1946 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered from 21 through 38.
Probate files are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1912-001 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Andover; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Bolton; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Columbia; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Hebron
Places:
Andover (Conn.); Bolton (Conn.); Columbia (Conn.); Hebron (Conn.)
Alternate Creator:
Connecticut. Probate Court (Hebron District)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2013-015, Record books, 1849-1941, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files from 1921-1946 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 23-37, 1851-1924; probate files, 1787-1915; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1912-001 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): October 26, 1912 (1787-1912); February 5, 1936 (1890-1934); July 28, 1942 (1914-1941); April 15, 1947 (1915-1946). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2013-015 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on October 11, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1849-1941; 9.25 cubic feet (18 volumes); 2013-015
  - Records, 1849-1951 (Volume 21)
    Volume 21 is for the Hebron probate district.
  - Records, 1851-1856 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1856-1858 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1858-1860 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1860-1862 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1862-1866 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1866-1870 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1870-1875 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1875-1881 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1881-1886 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1886-1891 (Volume 31)
  - Records, 1891-1894 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1894-1898 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1898-1901 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1901-1909 (Volume 35)
  - Records, 1907-1913 (Volume 36)
  - Records, 1913-1924 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1920-1941 (Volume 38)
- Probate files, 1787-1946; 22.5 cubic feet; 1912-001
  - A - Andrus, G (Drawer 1)
  - Andrus, J - Babcock, H. (Drawer 2)
  - Babcock, J - Baldwin (Drawer 3)
  - Barber - Benham (Drawer 4)
  - Bennett - Bingham (Drawer 5)
  - Birge - Blackman, E (Drawer 6)
  - Blackman, G. - Brewster (Drawer 7)
  - Brigham - Brown, N (Drawer 8)
  - Brown, O - Buell, J. (Drawer 9)
  - Buell, L - Calkins (Drawer 10)
  - Carbery - Carver, John (Drawer 11)
  - Carver, Joseph - Clark, A (Drawer 12)
  - Clark, C. - Cole (Drawer 13)
  - Collins - Colman, L. (Drawer 14)
  - Colman, M. - Cowles (Drawer 15)
  - Crain - Daly (Drawer 16)
  - Daniels - Dunham (Drawer 17)
  - Doan - Dunham, E. (Drawer 18)
  - Dunham, H. - Emerson (Drawer 19)
  - English - Fitch, B. (Drawer 20)
  - Fitch, C. - Fox (Drawer 21)
  - Franc - Fuller, John (Drawer 22)
  - Fuller, Julia - Gilbert, S. (Drawer 23)
  - Gilbert, W - Grover (Drawer 24)
  - Guar - Hau (Drawer 25)
  - Haw - Holbrook, John (Drawer 26)
  - Holbrook, Justin - House, J. (Drawer 27)
  - House, M. - Hunt, F. (Drawer 28)
  - Hunt, G. - Hutchins (Drawer 29)
  - Hutchinson - Isham (Drawer 30)
  - Janes - Jones, E. (Drawer 31)
  - Jones, H. - Keeney (Drawer 32)
  - Kellogg - Kingsbury (Drawer 33)
  - Kingsley - Laurenson (Drawer 34)
  - Lawson - Little, Elizabeth (Drawer 35)
  - Little, Esther - Loomis, A. (Drawer 36)
  - Loomis, Andrew - Loomis, Israel (Drawer 37)
  - Loomis, Jacob - Loomis William (Drawer 38)
  - Loomis, Z. - Lyman (Drawer 39)
  - Lyon - Maine (Drawer 40)
  - Mali - Maynard (Drawer 41)
  - Mead - Murdock (Drawer 42)
  - Murphy - Norton, D. (Drawer 43)
  - Norton, E. - Park (Drawer 44)
  - Parker - Perkins, G. (Drawer 45)
  - Perkins, J. - Phelps, E. (Drawer 46)
  - Phelps, F. - Polk (Drawer 47)
  - Pomeroy, Porter, Noah (Drawer 48)
  - Porter, Noah - Post, Jane (Drawer 49)
  - Post, Jedediah - Reed (Drawer 50)
  - Reich - Rittis (Drawer 51)
  - Robart - Root, E. (Drawer 52)
  - Root, H. - Rude, M. (Drawer 53)
  - Rudge - Sheriden (Drawer 54)
  - Shipman - Skinner (Drawer 55)
  - Slate - Sprague, R. (Drawer 56)
  - Sprague, S. - Strong, A. (Drawer 57)
  - Strong, B. - Sullard (Drawer 58)
  - Sullivan - Talcott, D. (Drawer 59)
  - Talcott, E. - Thompson, J. (Drawer 60)
  - Thompson, K. - Trythall, H. (Drawer 61)
  - Tucker - Walton (Drawer 62)
  - Warner - Way (Drawer 63)
  - Webler - Welles (Drawer 64)
  - West - White, John (Drawer 65)
  - White, Joseph- Williams (Drawer 66)
  - Willis - Wright, N. (Drawer 67)
  - Wright, R. - Zawinski; Miscellaneous (Drawer 68)
- Inventory Control Book, 1787-1946; T003073
  Index of the four accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1912-001
  Also known as the Godard Digest